I can't believe my little brother's married!
天啊，不敢相信我小弟结婚了
Why didn't you tell me you were eloping?
你们决定私订终身 怎么没跟我说？
Well,we were at court, eating lunch
一切都发生得很自然 我们在法院吃中饭
Why were you at the courthouse?
等等，你们干嘛去法院？
We were having lunch.
吃中饭啊
We were like...
那时的感觉就像是…
...we're here,we're having lunch. Let's get married! Right?
既然都来法院吃中饭了 不如就顺便结婚吧
A year ago,I didn't know I had a brother. Now I have a sister!
一年前我还不知道自己有弟弟 现在又多了个妹妹
Oh,it's so great.
真是太棒了
Okay.
好了
够了
Stop it! Don't!
别再亲了
I'll get you a gift now.
我得送你们新婚礼物才行
Is there anything you need?
你们有需要什么吗？
We've been trying to get pregnant since we got engaged,to get a jump on things.
我们订婚后就一直想怀孕 心想越早生越好
No one's getting any younger.
总是年轻不再了嘛
Because the thing is,we're not able to,you know,conceive.
不过重点是我们没办法… 成功做人
We've seen a bunch of doctors.
我们试过所有方法 看了一堆医生
They say that our only chance to have a baby...
对，他们说我们若想生小孩
...is that if they take my sperm, her egg,put it together in a dish...
唯有把我的精子和她的卵子 放进培养皿里头
...and put it into another girl.
再放进另一个女孩的子宫里
We were wondering if you could be that girl.
不知道你愿不愿意 让我们把受精卵放进去？
That's a really nice gift.
这真是个很棒的礼物
I was thinking of a gravy boat.
我还以为 你们会想要个是酱料皿呢
We know it's a lot to ask.
我们知道这个要求很过份
We don't have anyone else to go to. We could pay someone...
但我们求助无门 本想找别人做代理孕母
...but we don't have that kind of money.
但我们没那笔钱
Plus,you know,you're family and,you know...
再加上你又是家人
...I just don't want my baby to grow into some chick I don't know,you know?
我也不想把孩子 放进不认识的女孩肚子里
Don't give us an answer yet, think about it.
不急着回答，你考虑看看
And if you say no, we'll totally understand.
若你拒绝，我们也能完全了解
Okay. Okay.
好吧…
And we were wondering if you could give us a ride down to the train station.
对，能不能载我们去火车站？
Well,actually,we kind of need an answer to that one right now.
这问题可能要马上回答才行
The One with Phoebe's Uterus
菲比的子宫
rainystar压制iPod-MP4
Check it out! Guess what job I just got.
大伙照过来 猜我得到了什么工作？
I don't know,but Donald Trump wants his blue blazer black.
不知道，但是唐纳川普 想把他的蓝色外套黑回去
What?
什么？
Blue blazer back. He wants it back.
把蓝色外套要回去，是要回去
You said "black." Why would he want his blue blazer black?
你刚才是说“黑” 他把蓝外套黑回去干嘛？
Well,you know what I meant.
你知道我的意思
You messed it up.
是你说错了
You're stupid.
你真蠢
So,what job did you get?
乔伊，你是得到什么工作？
Tour guide at the museum. Ross got it for me.
在博物馆当导览员 罗斯帮我争取到的
Don't you have to be a dinosaur expert?
在博物馆当导览员 不是得要恐龙专家才行？
They give you all the information.
不尽然，他们会把资料都给你
It's like memorizing a script.
就跟背剧本一样
On your left you have a tyrannosaurus rex, from the Jurassic Period.
左方是侏罗纪的暴龙
Very nice.
不赖嘛
Yeah,actually,Joey, it's the Cretaceous Period.
其实暴龙是白垩纪的恐龙
But I can pronounce Jurassic.
是，但我念得出侏罗纪
Frank Jr. and Alice got married!
你们猜怎么着？ 法兰克和艾莉丝结婚了
Oh,my God!
天啊
They're having a baby!
而且他们就要生小孩了
They want me to grow it for them in my uterus!
而且他们还要用我的子宫来生
-My God! -Are you serious?
天啊 你是认真的吗？
You're thinking of having sex with your brother?
你在考虑和自己的弟弟上床？
Ew! And,oh,no!
恶心喔，才不是
They want me to be the surrogate.
他们只是要找我当代理孕母
It's her egg and his sperm. I'm the oven. It's their bun.
用他们的精子和卵子 我只负责当炉子烤面包
What did you say?
那你答应了没？
I had to think about it first, but what is there to think of?
他们说要先让我考虑一下 但是有啥好考虑的？
I'll be giving someone the greatest gift.
这是我能送出最重的厚礼
You'll carry their child and get them a Sony PlayStation?
你帮他们生小孩 还加赠新力PS游戏机？
This is an incredible thing to do.
这对他们一定是意义重大
But there are things to think about.
但是你得考虑到一些事
Yeah,you'd be pregnant. I mean,pregnant.
对啊，你会怀孕，怀孕耶
I know.
我知道啊
You'll put your body through an awful lot.
这对身体可是沉重负担
I mean,morning sickness,labor.
会害喜，还有分娩
It's all for somebody else.
还全都是为了别人
Yeah. What's your point?
是啊，你的重点是什么？
Well,the stuff I just mentioned.
我刚才说的就是啊
I couldn't do that.
这种事我一定做不到
I always figured the first time I had a baby, it'd be with someone I love.
我心想自己第一次怀孕 一定会是跟心爱的人
And that baby was,you know...
孩子出生之后…
...a keeper.
一定要留在自己身边
You were more supportive when I wanted to make denim furniture.
我当时要用牛仔布做家具时 你们都还比较支持
If you decide to do this, we'll be supportive like crazy.
如果你决定要这么做 我们一定支持得五体投地
Just think it through.
我们只是要你考虑清楚
Talk to somebody who's had a baby. Like your mom.
或许和生过小孩的人讨论一下 好比你母亲
My mom never gave birth. Oh! But my birth mom did!
我妈才没生过小孩呢 不过我的生母有
（中央咖啡馆）
I love this tushy! Can I take it to work with me?
我喜欢你的小屁屁 可以让我带去上班吗？
Yeah,sure. It's not mine anyway. It came with the pants.
没问题，反正不是我的 是买裤子附赠的
I am so jealous.
我嫉妒死了
You guys are just right there.
你们俩真的好投入
Yes.
是啊
Right where?
投入什么？
The beginning,where it's all sex and talking...
刚开始的热恋啊 上床、聊天…
...and sex and talking.
再上床、再聊天
You got to love the talking.
聊天的部分很棒
-And the sex? -We haven't had sex.
那上床呢？
我们还没上过床
What's the big deal? This is special.
有啥好大惊小怪的？ 这样才特别啊
I want our love to grow before moving to the next level.
在进入下一个阶段前 我要让爱情先滋长
Oh,Chandler,that is so nice.
钱德，这真的太棒了
That is really nice...
真的是很棒
...Iying!
骗人！
-No way is that the reason. -Why?
不可能会是那个原因 为什么？
Because you're not mature enough to understand that?
因为你太幼稚 无法了解那种事？
He's right. I'm totally lying.
不，罗斯说的对，我是在骗人
Then what is it?
那真相是什么？
Kathy's last boyfriend was Joey.
因为凯茜前任男友是乔伊
And you're afraid you won't be able to fill his shoes?
你担心自己…技不如人？
I'm afraid I won't make love as well as him.
不 我担心自己床上功夫没他行
-I was going for the metaphor. -I was saying the actual words.
我是想要用比喻的 我是直接说出来
He's had a lot of girlfriends. Doesn't mean he's great in bed.
没事啦，乔伊交过一卡车女友 这也不表示他床功一流
We share a wall.
我和他的卧房只隔了一道墙
Either he's great,or she liked to agree with him a lot.
若非他真的很强 就是他女友喜欢附和他
Loudly and a lot.
动不动就大声附和
All night long she'd agree.
从半夜附和到天亮
It'll be different. The sex will be great because you're in love.
你们的情况不一样 有爱做基础的性会更棒
-Just go for it. -Yeah,you should.
是吗？ 是啊 钱德，放手一试吧
All right. I'll sleep with my girlfriend.
好吧，我去跟女友一起睡
But I'm just doing it for you guys.
但我这全是为了你们
Now,the mastodon is from the semi-late Jurassic Period.
乳齿象来自侏罗纪半晚期
Isn't the mastodon from the Pliocene Epoch?
乳齿象不是上新世的吗？
This is a museum. No talking.
这里是博物馆，不能说话
Right down here we have...
这里的就是…
...a large foot.
大脚
And over here we have Ross Geller.
这位是罗斯盖勒
Everyone wave "hi" to Ross.
大家挥手和罗斯打招呼
Ross is one of our scientists. Look at him hard at work.
罗斯是馆内头号重要的科学家 你们看他工作有多努力
Okay,moving right along.
好，继续参观
Come on.
走吧
It's open. Come in.
门没关，请进
-I'm sorry I'm late. -That's okay.
抱歉迟到了 没关系
I had time to finish glazing my nipples.
我正好有时间替乳头上釉
You go all out when you're expecting company.
你为了见客还真是拼命
I was working on my pottery.
我说的是陶器
Oh! I didn't know that you did pot.
我不知道你会做…锅子
Mostly nudes. It combines my two passions: pottery and erotica.
对，大多没穿衣服 结合陶艺和色情这两种爱好
Erottery!
就叫做“陶情”吧
Thanks for coming out to see me.
谢谢你来看我
I thought it'd be a good idea to talk about this baby stuff in person.
我只是觉得生小孩这件事 还是当面聊比较好
I don't think it's a good idea.
菲比，我觉得这样不妥
Why not?
为什么？
You'd be giving up a baby.
因为你最后得要送走孩子
And I really don't
我不知道…
I don't know if anything I said...
不知道要怎么说...
...would make you understand the pain of giving up a baby.
...你才会懂 送走孩子会有多么痛苦
所以…
No,no,I understand the pain. Don't hurt the puppy!
不…我了解那种痛苦 不要伤害小狗
No,no. The puppy is yours.
不是啦…这小狗是你的了
-I get a puppy? -But for only three days.
我有小狗？ 对，但只能拥有三天
Why?
为什么？
I realize I don't have any right to start getting parent-y on you now.
我知道我现在没有权力 突然搬出妈妈的脸孔跟你说教
Look at me and not the puppy. It's very important.
菲比，麻烦别看小狗 看着我，我要说重要的事
I know what I'm talking about.
我知道我在说什么
I gave up two babies.
我送走过两个孩子
I only wish I had someone who'd given up babies that told me...
只希望当时能有前辈告诉我
...how terrible it is.
送走自己的小孩会有多痛苦
I really shouldn't have given you the puppy first.
早知道就别先把小狗给你
That's okay. No,we're listening.
没关系，我专心听你说
It'd be something you'd regret every day for the rest of your life.
我只是觉得送走孩子后 你会每天后悔直到死掉
So however hard it is for you to give up this puppy...
你到时送走这条小狗的痛苦
...it'd be a million times harder to give up a child.
还不及送走孩子的百万分之一
Okay,fair enough. Three days.
好，很合理，就养三天
Oh,it's time to take my ass out of the kiln.
该把屁股拿出烤窑了
Could you sit there? I'm saving this seat for my friend Ross.
你能不能坐对面？ 我帮朋友罗斯留了位置
You mean Dr. Geller?
你是说盖勒博士？
Doctor? I didn't know he had a nickname.
博士？我不知道他有这绰号
Oh,he won't sit here.
他才不会坐这里呢
Only people in white coats sit there.
穿白袍的都会坐在那里
Only people in blue blazers sit here.
穿蓝色外套的只能坐这里
-How come? -That's just the way it is.
为什么这样？ 就是这样
That's crazy.
岂有此理
Maybe it's crazy in a perfect world: a world without lab coats and blazers.
或许在不分蓝白的完美世界里 这样就会是岂有此理
But you not in a perfect world. You in a museum now.
但你不是活在完美世界 而且这里是博物馆
See that scientist?
看到那戴眼镜的科学家没？
He and I used to play together in grade school,but now....
想当年我们念小学还是玩伴 但现在呢？
Peter! Hey,Peter!
彼德！…
It's me! Rhonda,from P.S. 129?
我是朗妲，我们是同届的啊
I shared my pudding with you,man!
亏我把布丁分你吃过
I gave you my Snack Pack!
我还把点心棒送给你吃
See? He pretend he don't even hear me!
看到没？他假装通通没听到
Everyone's pretending they don't hear you.
我想大家都在假装没听到
I don't know about your jackets and separate tables...
我是不知道什么制服 还有你们分桌吃饭的事啦
...but Ross is my friend.
不过罗斯是我的死党
And if I save him a seat, he will sit in it.
若我帮他留了位置 我告诉你，他一定会坐
Here! I saved you a seat!
罗斯…来这里坐 我帮你留了位置
I'm cool here. I'll catch up with you later.
我坐这里就好了 之后再去找你聊
This is saved.
这个位置有人坐了
Gift shop.
她是礼品店的
I'm really,really sorry about what happened in the cafeteria today.
今天在自助餐厅的事很抱歉
You do what you got to do.
没什么，该怎么做就怎么做
The scientists and the tour guides never sit together.
不只是我而已 科学家和导览员从来不坐一起
Whatever.
随便啦
It's like that everywhere. Mon,back me up.
这种情况到处都有 摩妮卡，帮我说说话啊
Where you work,the waiters eat with the waiters.
在你工作的地方 侍者和侍者一起吃饭
And the chefs eat with the other chefs?
厨师和厨师吃饭，对吧？
I eat by myself in the alley, because everybody hates me.
我是自己躲在巷子里吃 因为大家都恨我
Okay,Rach,when was the last time you had lunch with the shipping clerks?
好，瑞秋，你上回 和运货员一起吃饭是何时？
I've never had lunch with the shipping clerks...
你听我说，我不常跟他们吃饭
...but it's totally different. They're not allowed in the executive cafeteria.
但这完全是两码子事 因他们不能进主管的自助餐厅
Oh,I see what you're saying.
我懂你的意思了
Look,Ross.
罗斯，你听我说
It's no big deal.
这没啥大不了的啦
You wear a white coat. I wear a blue blazer.
你穿白袍，我穿蓝色外套
If that means we can't be friends at work,so be it.
若这表示我们上班不能当朋友 那就这样吧
I understand,you know?
我能了解
When I'm in a play and you're in the audience,I don't talk to you.
我演舞台剧，你坐观众席 我也不会跟你说话，是吧？
So it's,you know,it's cool.
所以没事了
I'll see you tomorrow.
明天见
When we're in the audience, he doesn't talk but he does wave.
我们坐在观众席 他是没说话，但有跟我们招手
Who's my puppy? Who's my puppy? Who's my puppy?
我的小狗好不好呀？…
-Have you named him yet? -No,I don't want to get attached.
你帮它取名字没？ 没有，我不想陷下去
-Can I hold him? -Sure. Here.
可以让我抱抱吗？ 当然可以
-Come here,squirmy. Hello -Not like that. No.
来，给我抱抱 不是那样抱啦
Why's Phoebe singing to Karl Malden?
菲比干嘛唱歌给卡尔马登听？
I think it's time for puppy to go out again.
小狗又应该出去了
Come on,let's go to the balcony.
走，我们去阳台
The street. Come on,let's go to the street.
什么？ 去街上，走，我们去街上
Don't go on the balcony until after I get back.
在我回来之前，别去阳台
So did you do it?
你们做了没？
Yes,yes,we had the sex.
有…我们上床了
It was bad?
糟糕，不好喔？
It was fine,but she didn't agree with me as strongly as with Joey.
好是好，但是她附和我的程度 不像附和乔伊那样强烈
She was like,"l see your point. I'm all right with it."
感觉像是“我了解，无所谓”
There's not always a lot of agreement the first time.
第一次的互动总是比较生疏
Yeah. Not for girls,anyway. Guys agree like that.
对，女生要慢慢来 不像男生一碰就互动了
Look,you have to help me.
你们得帮帮我
I mean....
我是说…
I know what to do with a woman. It's always nice.
我知道怎么在床上取悦女人 我知道步骤，一直也都很好
I need to know...
但我需要知道…
...what makes it go from nice to:
要怎么从“好”进阶到…
"My God! Somebody's killing her in there!"
“老天 那砘锶盟欲仙欲死”
I'll show you something a lot of guys don't know.
我来开释一个 很多男人不知道的事
瑞秋，麻烦把那本子给我
All right.
好吧
Now.
来罗
You don't have to draw an actual Whoa,she's hot!
你不用真的画出… 哇，她身材真惹火
Everyone knows the erogenous zones.
大家都知道性感带在哪里
You got one,two,three...
有一、二、三…
...four...
四…
...five,six and seven.
五、六，还有七
There are seven?
性感带有七个？
Let me see that.
我看看
Oh,yeah.
对，没错
That's one?
那里也算一个？
Kind of an important one.
还蛮重要的呢
I was looking at it upside down.
反过来看会有误差嘛
Well,you know,sometimes that helps.
有时候反过来也不错
Most guys will hit one,two,three and then go to seven and set up camp.
男人大多数爱抚过一、二、三 就直接跳到第七个，结束比赛
That's bad?
那样不好吗？
At Disneyland,you don't spend the whole day on the Matterhorn.
你去迪士尼乐园 也不会整天只玩马特洪雪橇啊
You might if it were like seven.
若那是第七个就有可能
All right,the important thing is to take your time.
重点是慢慢来
You want to hit them all...
七个性感带都要照顾到
...mix them up. Keep them on their toes.
还要搭配混和使用 就像踮脚那样维持紧绷
Oh,toes!
脚趾！
For some people.
有些人的脚趾会兴奋嘛
All right.
好吧
You could start out with a little one.
你可以先小小来个一
A two.
再来二
A one,two,three.
一、二、三搭配
A three.
一个三
A five.
一个五
A four.
一个四
A three,two.
来个三和二
Two. A two,four,six.
二，再配个二、四、六
Two,four,six.
二、四、六
Four. Two.
四、二
Two. Four,seven!
二，四和七
Five,seven! Six,seven!
五配七，六配七
Seven! Seven!
七！…
Seven! Seven! Seven! Seven! Seven! Seven!
Seven!
And there you are.
这样就可以了
Yeah,that'll work.
对，那样会有效的
Dr. Geller? There's a seat here.
盖勒博士，这里有位置
Thank you,Dr. Phillips.
菲利普斯博士，谢谢你
But I'm having my lunch...
但我的午餐…
...at this table. Here in the middle.
要在这张桌子上吃 中间这一张
I'm having my lunch...
我的午餐…
...right here with my good friend,Joey.
就在这里和好友乔伊一起吃
If he'll sit with me.
若他愿意跟我坐一起的话
I will sit with you,Dr. Geller.
盖勒博士，我跟你坐
You know...
你们知道吗…
...we work in a museum of natural history.
我们在自然史博物馆工作
And yet,there is something...
然而却有一件事…
...unnatural...
很不自然
...about the way we eat lunch.
我们吃中饭的方式很不自然
Now,I want you to know...
我要让你们知道
...it took a tour guide to show this scientist the error of his ways.
这位导览员让我这科学家 了解到自己处事方法的错误
You might even say he took me on a tour...
甚至可以说他带领我 看到了...
...of myself.
...我自己的内心
Yeah,that was me.
对，他说的就是我
I look around,and you know what I see? I see division.
我环顾这自助餐听的四周 看到了什么？我看到隔阂
Division between people in white coats and people in blue blazers.
穿白袍的人和穿蓝外套的人 彼此有着隔阂
I ask myself,"My God,why?"
我扪心自问 “天啊，这是为什么？”
Now,I say we shed these coats...
我建议大家脱掉…
...that separate us.
造成我们隔阂的这些外套
And we get to know the people underneath.
才能认识衣服里面的人
I'm Ross!
我是罗斯！
I'm divorced and I have a kid!
我离过婚，有个小孩
I'm Joey! I'm an actor!
我是乔伊，我是个演员
I don't know squat about dinosaurs!
我对恐龙一窍不通
I'm Ted,and I just moved here, and New York really scares me.
我是泰德，一个月前才搬来 纽约真是吓坏我了
-There you go! -Hang in there,Teddy!
这就对了！ 泰德，你要撑住
I'm Andrew.
我是安德鲁
And I didn't pay for this pear.
这颗西洋梨我没付钱
Okay. Good for you.
好，有你的
I'm Rhonda! And these aren't real!
我是朗妲，这一对不是真的！
Wow,Rhonda.
朗妲…
-I'm Scott. -Yeah,okay,Scott!
我是史考特 帮史考特加油
I flip the light switch on and off 17 times when I leave a room...
我在离开一个房间之前 一定要连续开灯关灯17次
...or my family will die.
不然我全家都会死光光
My mom's gonna be here any minute.
我妈随时会来
I can't. I can't give him up.
我没办法，我不能送走它
Yes,no. I can.
不对，我可以
I don't want to.
我不想
But I can.
但是我可以
No.
不行
I can't watch this. It's like Sophie's Choice.
我再看下去一定会崩溃 这就像是“苏菲的选择”
You know,I never saw that.
我从没看过那部电影
Oh,it was only okay.
其实很普通而已啦
I can't do this.
我办不到
My mom was right. If I can't give him up...
我妈妈说的对 若我连一条狗都舍不得
...there's no way I can give up a baby.
怎么可能送走自己生的小孩
Frank and Alice are going to be so crushed.
法兰克和艾莉丝一定会很受伤
What else can I give them? A kidney!
我能给他什么别的？肾脏？
We were in the neighborhood.
我们正好在附近
We want to let you know that there's still no pressure.
我们顺路过来是要让你知道 还是不要有压力
If there was something you wanted to say,we'll be right there.
但是如果你有事要跟我们说 我们就坐在那里喝咖啡
Who's this little guy?
这个小砘锸撬？
He's so cute! He reminds me of my old dog,Tumor.
真可爱 让我想起我的老狗肿瘤
You are so precious, I could take you home.
瞧你可爱的，真想带你回家
Why don't you?
有何不可呢？
-Are you serious? -Yeah.
你是说真的？ 是啊
Thanks.
多谢了
-What are you doing? -I'm okay with this.
你在干嘛？ 这样不会让我难过
You know why? Because look at them.
你们知道原因吗？看看他们
Look how happy they are.
看他们高兴成那样
And I made that,so you know....
这是我的功劳，所以…
It'll be a million times harder to give up a baby,but oh,my God!
我知道送走自己生出来的孩子 一定会难上百万倍…
It'll feel a million times better,right?
但到时的快乐 一定也会是百万倍，对吧？
I'll do this. I want to carry your baby.
决定了，我要怀你们的孩子
Thank you so much!
真是太感谢了
You don't know what this means to us.
这对我们意义非凡
I think I'm going to cry!
天啊，我都快哭了
It's going to be so great.
一定会很棒的
-What's going on? -I gave them the puppy.
怎么回事？ 我把小狗给了他们
It made them so happy, I decided to carry their baby.
看他们高兴成那样 我决定帮他们怀小孩
-Phoebe -No,I know.
菲比… 你不用说，我知道
We're different,though.
不过你我是完全不同的人
This is a different situation.
而且情况也完全不同
I am not going to regret this.
我知道我这样做绝不会后悔
I understand all that.
你说的我都了解
It's just,that was my puppy.
只是…那小狗是我的耶
Would you ever be a surrogate?
你愿意帮别人当代理孕母吗？
Depends who asked.
要看是谁要我帮忙
What if I asked?
如果是我要你帮忙呢？
Oh,Mon,sure!
摩妮卡，那我当然愿意啊
-Really? -Yes.
真的？ 是啊
You're not asking me,are you?
你不是真要我帮忙吧？
-No. -Yes. Totally.
不是 我当然帮你，一定帮
Thank you! Thank you!
谢谢你…
Thank you! Yes,thank you!
谢谢你 太谢谢你了！